it is almost a bedtime
I've yet to put up a video today because
I've been playing around with this
analogy that I'm taking pictures I can
do a Twitter post tomorrow because it's
not happening tonight but I have this
idea and I that we're all equal and how
to actually explain that in a way that
makes sense to people
my background is ecology and so I like
to explain it like every individual is a
species in and of themselves you're not
broken just because you sleep all day
you're a cat you're not you know like we
all have different niches within the
ecosystem the issue with that like all
of the analogies that I want a cup with
to explain it is that our connotation is
different for different species we don't
think of an ant or a fly or a plant or a
tiger as equal to one another
we don't talk about them like they're
equal to one another even though they
are all how an ecosystem runs you can't
have an ecosystem without all of it the
same with the analogy of a machine a car
there's an engine and fuel gauges and it
only works when it comes together so I
have been playing with children's
puzzles all evening because that to me
right now is the perfect dinner watching
a and it's still working out I'm still
gonna be written tomorrow but I wanted
to do a video today to torque it to
explain this and showcase how well my
brain works in the evening I guess but
there's just so much about it that like
each puzzle piece depending on what your
puzzle is you're going to be a different
color a different size a different shape
and yet none of them are better sure you
start a puzzle with the with the edge
pieces or you start it with the corner
pieces and you work your way in and you
find light colors together and that is
also how we are gonna do this and create
the global cooperative it's about well
everyone else is arguing about who is
the best piece
who is the best didn't actually realize
their pieces they're arguing who is the
best without realizing that they
actually fit together that if they just
found their neighbor they just found the
person that they connect to it somebody
who has a lot of the same color but a
slightly different pattern and got
together and then found somebody else to
connect to and somebody else to connect
to eventually a picture emerges and you
can see a higher form a higher function
and when you're big enough everyone else
around you can see it as well and more
pieces are at it and more pieces are at
it until you are an entire puzzle the
same time it's not that 7.5 billion of
us make up one puzzle we are hundreds
and hundreds of thousands of puzzles and
so you have a place to fit within your
puzzle but if you don't fulfill that
role there will be other puzzles that
that are still able to be built without
you fulfilling your role but your puzzle
won't be I no matter how damaged you are
as a puzzle piece your whole entire
puzzle is wrecked by you not being part
of it by you being missing that puzzle
yours gets thrown out and so I just
wanted to come on and share that so that
there is a video for today because I've
made a commitment to do a video six days
a week Sunday being my day off
and so I am going to go to bed now and
think about puzzle pieces and more of
this analogy as well as I have written
down here that like my role in this
although I am my own puzzle piece I can
see the puzzle piece but that I can see
the image that is so much to this puzzle
piece analogy like even just the puzzle
piece knowledge I won't explain so much
for that like if you're walking through
life as your puzzle piece you actually
don't even know what you look like
there's no mirror to show you so you
don't know which puzzle you're a part of
everyone else is telling you were wrong
maybe you actually are wrong in that
you're born in the wrong puzzle box
telling you that you're inferior but
you're just in the wrong puzzle box you
got to leave and go and find your your
space and what I have to offer the world
what I'm talking about with the global
cooperative is that I see the image I
can actually see how we all fit together
and I don't know I'm excited about my
analogy so I will be doing a new video
tomorrow Turin will be on and I'll be
doing this Twitter thread or maybe a
better video on this take care please
like and subscribe